ISAIAH **FRANCOIS**

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

- francoiscoding.netlify.app/
- **** 3529893703
- **♀** Clermont, Fl
- in francoiscoding
- FrancoisCoding

A software development and performance engineering expert with 4+ years of experience in developing quality assured applications. A collaborative developer and engineer with experience and education in the hardware and software sides of technology who thrives on discovery and accelerating performance.

Skills

PROGRAMMING TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

Python

ReactJS

Express

Git

SOL

Redux SASS

MongoDB

Firebase

Cypress Testing

Typescript

web3.js

NextJS

ethers.is

Docker Netlify

Vercel

TailwindCSS

React Native

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Adaptability

Technical Troubleshooting and Debugging

Software and Engineering Documentation

Systems Architecture and **Operations**

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Performance Engineering and Measurement

Employment

SpeechifAl

Lead Front-end Developer

Remote Feb. 2021 to Current

SpeechifAI is the digital campaign suite for word-of-mouth marketing with ~\$300k in annual revenues and investments

- Created sharing platform that allowed users to seamlessly post to social networks. Driving daily user engagement from ~600 - 5000 recurring users.
- Developed website embedding system to increase user engagement. This increased monthly recurring revenue 283.436% and 3x paying clients.

Department of Defence

Front End Developer

Oct. 2020 to Dec. 2020

Department of Defense is an executive branch department of the federal government charged with coordinating and supervising all agencies and functions of the government directly related to national security and the United States Armed Forces.

• Created mobile app that allowed users to manage and assign work orders to different buildings and bases.

Bloom Institute of Technology

Remote

Remote

Team Lead

Oct. 2019 to July 2020

- Mentored 10+ students on how to learn effectively and solve programming problems.
- Provided daily feedback and issue resolution of all curriculum through Slack interface.
- · Led daily standup meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate sharing of ideas and work progress, and provide guidance for that week's study material.
- Delivered one-on-one feedback and code review on a weekly basis, giving feedback on areas of improvement.

Projects

DevChat

Solo full-stack chat application allowing users to chat in real-time and video call any user across the platform. Firebase| React.JS | Semantic UI | Redux | Moment

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can have conversations and video call.
- Utilized the Jutsu Video API in order to establish video connections between users.

React Movies

Solo IMDB style Web Application that provides up to date movie information and details. ReactJS | Bootstrap

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view information on over 10,000 of the latest movies released.
- Utilized The Movie Database API in order to display all information about latest movie titles to users.

Beach Resort

E-commerce application featuring a hotel where users can view featured rooms, filter through rooms, receive updated room information and book rooms through PayPal

React.JS | Contentful | Redux | PayPal

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a e-commerce platform where users can book a room at a virtual hotel.
- Utilized the Contentful CMS to create database to store rooms and the PayPal API to initialize user purchasing.

Education

Bloom Institute of Technology · May 2019 to Feb. 2020 Full Stack Web Development

Remote